<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Benchmark xmlns="http://checklists.nist.gov/xccdf/1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="iOS-6" xsi:schemaLocation="http://checklists.nist.gov/xccdf/1.1 xccdf-1.1.4.xsd" resolved="false" xml:lang="en-US">
  <status date="2014-01-13-05:00">draft</status>
  <title>Guide to the Secure Configuration of Apple iOS 6</title>
  <description>This guide is designed to provide comprehensive discussion of
  security-relevant configuration settings for Apple iOS 6. Providing system
  administrators with such information enables them to securely configure
  systems under their control in a variety of network roles. This guide also
  provides policy makers with a comprehensive catalog of settings, from which
  security baselines can be constructed. The XCCDF format enables granular
  selection and adjustment of settings, and their association with OVAL and
  OCIL content provides an automated checking capability. Transformations of
  this document, and its associated automated checking content, are capable of
  providing baselines that meet a diverse set of policy
  objectives.</description>
  <notice id="terms_of_use">Do not attempt to implement any of the settings in
  this guide without first testing them in a non-operational environment. The
  creators of this guidance assume no responsibility whatsoever for its use by
  other parties, and makes no guarantees, expressed or implied, about its
  quality, reliability, or any other characteristic.</notice>
  <front-matter>SCAP-on-Apple Project</front-matter>
  <version>0.5</version><Profile id="byod">
<title>Profile for iOS Devices in BYOD Scenarios</title>
<description>This profile is designed for iOS devices in BYOD scenarios.</description>
<select idref="disable_simple_value_for_passcode" selected="true"/>
<select idref="require_alphanumeric_value_for_passcode" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_minimum_passcode_length" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_minimum_number_of_complex_characters" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_maximum_passcode_age" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_auto_lock_time" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_grace_period_for_device_lock" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_screen_capture" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_safari_autofill" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_safari_fraud_warning" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_safari_pop_up_blocking" selected="true"/>
<select idref="accept_cookies_from_visited_sites_only" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_user_acceptance_of_untrusted_tls_certificates" selected="true"/>
<select idref="force_encrypted_backups" selected="true"/>
<select idref="prevent_moving_messages_between_mail_accounts" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_mail_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_s_mime_support_for_mail_if_needed" selected="true"/>
<select idref="prevent_moving_messages_between_activesync_accounts" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_activesync_communications" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_s_mime_support_for_activesync_if_needed" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_ldap_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_caldav_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_subscribed_calendar_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_carddav_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="sign_messages" selected="true"/>
<select idref="check_out_when_removed" selected="true"/>
</Profile><Profile id="enterprise">
<title>Profile for Enterprise-Controlled iOS Devices</title>
<description>This profile is designed for enterprise-controlled iOS devices.</description>
<select idref="disable_simple_value_for_passcode" selected="true"/>
<select idref="require_alphanumeric_value_for_passcode" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_minimum_passcode_length" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_minimum_number_of_complex_characters" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_maximum_passcode_age" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_auto_lock_time" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_passcode_history" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_grace_period_for_device_lock" selected="true"/>
<select idref="set_maximum_number_of_failed_attempts" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_installation_of_third_party_apps" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_screen_capture" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_safari_autofill" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_safari_fraud_warning" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_safari_pop_up_blocking" selected="true"/>
<select idref="accept_cookies_from_visited_sites_only" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_icloud_backups" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_icloud_document_sync" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_icloud_photo_stream" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_sending_diagnostic_data_to_apple" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_user_acceptance_of_untrusted_tls_certificates" selected="true"/>
<select idref="force_encrypted_backups" selected="true"/>
<select idref="disable_auto_join_for_wi_fi" selected="true"/>
<select idref="prevent_moving_messages_between_mail_accounts" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_mail_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_s_mime_support_for_mail_if_needed" selected="true"/>
<select idref="prevent_moving_messages_between_activesync_accounts" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_activesync_communications" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_s_mime_support_for_activesync_if_needed" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_ldap_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_caldav_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_subscribed_calendar_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="enable_ssl_for_carddav_connections" selected="true"/>
<select idref="sign_messages" selected="true"/>
<select idref="check_out_when_removed" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_query_of_general_settings" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_query_of_network_settings" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_query_of_security_settings" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_query_of_restrictions" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_query_of_configuration_profiles" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_query_of_provisioning_profiles" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_query_of_applications" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_configuration_profiles" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_provisioning_profiles" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_or_disallow_remote_change_of_device_password" selected="true"/>
<select idref="allow_remote_wipe" selected="true"/>
</Profile>
  <Value id="conditional_clause" type="string" operator="equals">
    <title>A conditional clause for check statements.</title>
    <description>A conditional clause for check statements.</description>
    <value>This is a placeholder.</value>
  </Value>
  <Group id="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><description><b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Purpose.</b> This document provides security-related usage and configuration
recommendations for Apple iOS devices such as the iPhone, iPad, and iPod touch.
This document does not constitute government policy, nor is it an endorsement
of any particular platform; its purpose is solely to provide security guidance.
This guide may outline procedures required to implement or secure certain
features, but it is also not a general-purpose configuration manual.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Audience.</b>  This guide is primarily intended for network/system
administrators deploying Apple’s iOS devices or supporting their integration
into enterprise networks.  Some information relevant to IT decision makers and
users of the devices is also included. Readers are assumed to possess basic
network and system administration skills for Mac OS X or Microsoft Windows
systems, and they should have some familiarity with Apple’s documentation and
user interface conventions.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Scope.</b> Apple's mobile devices, including the iPhone and iPad, are
prominent examples of a new generation of mobile devices that combine into a
single device the capabilities of a cellular phone, laptop computer, portable
music player, camera, audio recorder, GPS receiver and other electronics. The
capabilities of such devices are considerable but, as with any information
system, also pose some security risks. Design features can seriously mitigate
some risks, but others must be considered as part of a careful, holistic risk
decision that also respects the capabilities enabled by such devices.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
Security guidance for mobile devices must cut across many previously discrete
boundaries between technologies. For example, scrupulous deployment of an
iPhone includes consideration not just the settings on the device itself, but
those of the Wi-Fi networks to which it will connect, the VPNs through which it
will tunnel, and the servers from which it will receive its configuration. This
guide provides recommendations for the settings on an iOS device itself, as
well as closely-related information for the network and configuration resources
upon which deployment of iOS devices depends.
</description>
    
    
    <Group id="how_to_use_this_guide"><title>How to Use This Guide</title>
      
      <Group id="read_sections_completely_and_in_order"><title>Read Sections Completely and in Order</title><description> Each section tends to build on information discussed in prior
sections. Each section should be read and understood completely. Instructions
should never be blindly applied. Relevant discussion may occur immediately
<i xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">after</i> instructions for an action, so be sure to read the whole section
before beginning implementation. Careful consideration is essential for
deploying iOS devices in an enterprise environment where multiple supporting
devices and software components may need to be configured properly in order to
function. </description>
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="understand_the_purpose_of_this_guidance"><title>Understand the Purpose of this Guidance</title><description> The purpose of the guidance is to provide seurity-relevant
configuration recommendations. It does not imply the suitability or
unsuitability of any product for any particular situation, which entails a risk
decision. </description>
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="limitations"><title>Limitations</title><description> This guide is limited in its scope to security-related issues.
This guide does not claim to offer comprehensive configuration guidance. For
general configuration and implementation guidance refer to other sources such
as Apple. </description>
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="test_in_non_production_environment"><title>Test in Non-Production Environment</title><description> To the extent possible, guidance should be tested in a
non-production environment before deployment. Ensure that any test environment
simulates the configuration in which the devices will be deployed as closely as
possible. </description>
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="formatting_conventions"><title>Formatting Conventions</title><description> Commands intended for shell execution, file paths, and
configuration file text, are featured in a <xhtml:code xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">monospace font</xhtml:code>. Menu
options and GUI elements will be set in a <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bold, sans-serif font</b>.
Settings appropriate to the device itself will be typeset in-line (i.e.
<b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings &gt; Airplane Mode</b>). Actionable instructions are typically
embedded in a box. </description>
        
        
      </Group>
    </Group>
    <Group id="general_principles"><title>General Principles</title><description> The following general principles motivate much of the advice in
this guide and should also influence any configuration decisions that are not
explicitly addressed. </description>
      
      
      <Group id="encrypt_transmitted_data_whenever_possible"><title>Encrypt Transmitted Data Whenever Possible</title><description> Data transmitted over a network, whether via wire or wirelessly,
is susceptible to passive monitoring. Whenever practical mechanisms exist for
encrypting this data-in-transit, they should be applied. Even if data is
expected to be transmitted only over a local network, it should still be
encrypted if possible. Encrypting authentication data, such as passwords, is
particularly important. iOS’s support for SSL, WPA2, and IPsec protocols
demonstrates its capabilities, when such features are activated, to adhere to
this principle. </description>
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="encrypt_stored_data_whenever_possible"><title>Encrypt Stored Data Whenever Possible</title><description> Data on mobile devices is particularly susceptible to compromise
due to loss of physical control. Whenever practical solutions exist, they
should be employed to protect this data. The Data Protection API on iOS devices
is used by some applications, and demonstrates the devices’ capability to
provide such protection. Drawing on applications which use this capability (and
ensuring that internally-developed enterprise applications also use it), and
setting an appropriately complex passcode, follow this principle.
</description>
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="minimize_software_to_minimize_vulnerability"><title>Minimize Software to Minimize Vulnerability</title><description> The easiest and simplest way to avoid the vulnerabilities in a
particular piece of software is to avoid installing the software altogether.
Hundreds of thousands of 3rd-party applications, or “apps,” written by
thousands of different developers are available for iOS devices. These
developers may have willfully or accidentally introduced vulnerabilities. For
some environments, a particular app may fulfill a mission-critical need. In
other cases an app might needlessly introduce additional risk to the system.
Certain risk scenarios may call for minimizing apps. BYOD scenarios, on the
other hand, generally imply the consideration and acceptance of such risks.
</description>
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="leverage_security_features_never_disable_them"><title>Leverage Security Features, Never Disable Them</title><description> Security features should be effectively used to improve a
system’s resistance to attacks. These features can improve a system’s
robustness against attack for only the cost of a little effort spent doing
configuration. For example, iOS’s enforcement of code signing of apps provides
assurance of integrity both during installation and at runtime. Disabling this
feature through the use of “jailbreaking” tools provided by the hacker
community significantly decreases an iOS device’s resistance to attack.
</description>
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="grant_least_privilege"><title>Grant Least Privilege</title><description> Grant the least privilege necessary for users to perform tasks.
The more privileges (or capabilities) that a user has, the more opportunities
he or she will have to enable the compromise of the system (and be a victim of
such a compromise). For example, a configuration profile can disallow use of
the Safari web browser and the camera. Disabling the camera prevents a
malicious or careless user from photographing sensitive areas, while disabling
Safari helps ensure the user is protected from any web-based attacks (albeit at
significant loss of capability). Similarly, it is possible to restrict the
installation of third party apps, and this may be the right balance between
security and functionality for some environments. </description>
        
        
      </Group>
    </Group>
    <Group id="risks_mitigations_and_consequences"><title>Risks, Mitigations, and Consequences</title><rationale> Understanding the risks – and available mitigations – involved in
the deployment of smartphone platforms such as iOS provides a background for
certain risk decisions. An attacker who has compromised any mobile device, and
can remotely maintain control of that device, can use this access to gather a
great deal of information about the user of the device and his or her
environment. As described by NIST Special Publication 800-124, the
consequences of such attacks include: 
<ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li>collecting audio (“hot-microphone” eavesdropping)</li><li>using the cameras</li><li>geolocation of the device (and presumably the user)</li><li>collecting all data, including credentials stored on the device or accessed by it</li><li>acting as the user on any network to which the device later connects.</li></ul>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
The following table describes risks (with attack vector) along with applicable
mitigations that are either built into the iOS platform or can be employed by
administrators or users. The following table is provided as a summary for risk
decision makers - and to motivate administrators to apply mitigations whenever
practical. <i xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It should not be used to draw comparisons between iOS and other
platforms.</i>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><tr><th>Risk</th><th>Mitigation</th></tr><tr><td>Data Compromise due to Lost Device (still reachable over any network interface --- cellular or WiFi) </td><td>Enabling a Passcode provides protection for Apps that leverage the Data Protection API, such as Apple's Mail app and 3rd party apps, as well as for credential storage in Keychains. Using the latest hardware currently prevents usage of public Jailbreak tools to access other data on a lost device.  Activating a remote wipe can be performed via ActiveSync, MDM, or iCloud.  Find My iPhone or other geolocation could permit the lost device to be located. </td></tr><tr><td>Data Compromise due to Lost Device (not reachable over any network interface)</td><td>Enabling a Passcode encrypts some data on the device.  Using the latest hardware currently prevents usage of public Jailbreak tools to access other data on a lost device.</td></tr><tr><td>Data Compromise due to Casual Access Attempt</td><td>Enabling a Passcode prevents a casual snoop from accessing the device. Provide user training to stress importance of physical control at all times.</td></tr><tr><td>Data Compromise via Host Computer Backup/Sync </td><td>Ensure proper hygiene and configuration of systems used for backup/sync.
This may entail enterprise rollout of iTunes, to ensure protection of backup
data. Train users not to connect their device to any untrusted
computers/devices and provide additional AC outlet chargers. Encrypting iOS
device backups in iTunes can mitigate data loss if the host computer is later
compromised or lost. </td></tr><tr><td>Exploitation of Device via Malicious app </td><td>The Sandboxing feature prevents apps from carrying out certain malicious
activities. The App Store's app vetting process provides accountability for
developers, which discourages creation of malicious apps. Disabling the App
Store, or permitting only installation of Enterprise-created Apps, further
mitigates any threat from 3rd party app developers (at significant cost to
capability).</td></tr><tr><td>Exploitation of Device via Malicious WiFi Network </td><td>Apply software updates. Provide user training on connecting only to trusted
networks. Provide user training to encourage use of the VPN.  </td></tr><tr><td>Exploitation of Device via Bluetooth Communications</td><td>Apply software
updates.  Monitor compliance with MDM software. iOS only implements a small
subset of the available BlueTooth profiles, which decreases its likelihood to
contain vulnerabilities that would give rise to exploitation.</td></tr><tr><td>Exploitation of Device via Cellular Network (e.g. SMS/MMS, baseband communications)</td><td>Apply software updates.  Monitor compliance with MDM software.  Provide user training to ensure awareness during travel.</td></tr><tr><td>Exploitation of Device via Malicious Email or Web Page</td><td>Apply software updates, with particular vigilance after public release of jailbreak tools. Monitor compliance with MDM software.</td></tr></table>
</rationale>
      
      
    </Group>
  </Group>
  <Group id="deployment"><title>Configuration Deployment</title><description>This chapter presents information about creating and deploying
settings to iOS devices, which are generally contained in configuration
profiles. Configuration profiles are simply XML files that conform to Apple's
XML DTD and the plist format. Additional information is available at
<b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://www.apple.com/iphone/business/it-center/</b>.</description>
    
    
    <Group id="nature_of_configuration_profiles"><title>Nature of Configuration Profiles</title><description>Understand that a user who controls an iOS device can opt to erase
the device, which erases all data from the device including any configuration
profiles. Understand also that users can typically append further restrictive
settings, as well as services, onto the device, even in the presence of a
configuration profile.  Configuration Profile settings enforcement on the iOS
devices are cumulative indicating that they can further restrict existing
settings when applied.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
iOS configuration profiles specify a collection of settings that can control
some security-relevant behavior of an iOS device, but are not designed to
provide an enterprise with total, arbitrary control over the user's device.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
A "carrot and stick" approach can be employed to avoid tempting users to remove
a configuration profile (either directly or via device reset). Bind "carrots"
(such as credentials needed for enterprise access) to "sticks" (such as a
passcode policy) in a single configuration profile. Removing a configuration
profile implies that credentials necessary for accessing enterprise services
(such as VPN certificates or e-mail accounts) would also be lost, and thus deny
the user such services. Also in this case, MDM software would become unable to
query the device and the enterprise would be alerted as to the device's
unmanaged status.</description>
      
      
    </Group>
    <Group id="mobile_device_management_software"><title>Mobile Device Management Software</title><description> Third-party MDM products, as well as Apple’s own OS X Server, can
automate the deployment of configuration profiles and carry out the operational
management of devices. Configuration profiles can also be provided via secure
web-based services. Configuration profiles can also be created using Apple’s
iPhone Configuration Utility ("iPCU"), but it does not provide mechanisms for
automated deployment or reporting. iPCU provides a convenient means of
surveying the settings which can be deployed to devices, although there is no
guarantee that a particular MDM product will support all settings.
</description>
      
      
      <Group id="select_mobile_device_management_mdm_software"><title>Select Mobile Device Management (MDM) Software</title><description> Select an MDM product which uses Apple’s MDM API, unless
enterprise management of the devices is not needed. </description><rationale> Apple’s MDM API provides the supported mechanism for enterprise
device management, and various 3rd party vendors have built products upon it.
For more information, see <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://www.apple.com/iphone/business/it-center/deployment-mdm.html</b>.
</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="understand_capabilities_of_mdm_software"><title>Understand Capabilities of MDM Software</title><description> Mobile device management software may also include features that
are not part of the supported Apple MDM API: 
<ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li>"Jailbreak detection” can
determine if a user has chosen to jailbreak his or her device, which is a
useful feature for enterprises who monitor compliance. However, it does not
provide high assurance that a device has not been maliciously jailbroken by a
sophisticated attacker. The situation is analogous to “root detection” on
another mobile platform. It is also analogous to the historical and difficult
problem of rootkit detection on desktop or server operating systems. In all
these cases, the operating system itself becomes compromised. Since it alone
operates at the most privileged levels, there are limits to the extent to which
any add-on software can "ask a liar if he is lying."
<br/>
<br/>
The system’s cryptographically-verified boot process, runtime enforcement of
code signatures, app sandboxing mechanism, controlled software distribution
model via "app stores", and rapid software update capability very strongly
address the problem of jailbreak-based attacks by themselves. Using add-on
software to query for signs of jailbreak may provide an additional layer of
defense. </li><br/><br/><li>"Secure containers" can provide data-at-rest protection and data-in-transit
protection. These are typically software libraries included by 3rd party apps,
which then make use of their functionality instead of that provided by the
system’s software libraries. These "containers" (which are really just apps)
can be useful if the system’s capable, built-in mechanisms which already
provide these features do not meet particular requirements. Note, however, that
they cannot protect their contents against privileged code running on the
device, such as would result from a sophisticated, malicious jailbreak attack
during system operation.
<br/>
<br/>
They should also <i>not be confused</i> with the Sandboxing feature of
the iOS kernel as described in [Blazakis]. Rather, the Sandboxing feature
strongly addresses the problem of malicious or co-opted apps trying to perform
undesirable activities on the system (such as elevating their privileges) in
the first place. Sandboxing constitutes a significant obstacle to attackers,
but it does not allow apps to (rather inconceivably) protect themselves if the
underlying operating system is compromised. App sandboxing may serve as a means
of jailbreak detection as discussed above, in that an app which can access
beyond its Sandbox may infer that it is running on a compromised device.
</li></ul>
</description>
        
        
      </Group>
    </Group>
    <Group id="deploying_configuration_profiles"><title>Deploying Configuration Profiles</title><description> After a configuration profile is created — typically in an MDM console — it must be deployed to devices. This section discusses methods available for installing a configuration profile onto an iOS device, along with their security implications.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<i xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Customizing profiles to individual users implies embedding sensitive authentication information within transmitted profiles. This introduces a need for confidentiality during transmission of such files.</i></description>
      
      
      <Group id="deploy_over_the_air_with_encryption_and_authentication"><title>Deploy Over-the-Air with Encryption and Authentication</title><description> If configuration profiles will be deployed over-the-air, ensure
use of authentication and encryption.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
If the iPhone can authenticate a configuration profile during its installation, the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings &gt; General &gt; Profile</b> screen will display <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Verified</b>.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
Over-the-air deployment that is authenticated and encrypted requires the
support of enterprise infrastructure, such as directory services, an enterprise
certificate trusted by iPhone, an SCEP server, and a web server. The server
component of MDM products may provide some of this infrastructure.</description><rationale> Deploying configuration profiles to a device over-the-air consists
of three major steps:
<ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li><i>Authentication</i> of the user, typically leveraging
existing directory services.
</li><li><i>Enrollment</i>, which involves the device transmitting device-specific information to the enterprise, and receiving a device certificate in return.
</li><li><i>Installation</i> of an encrypted, authenticated configuration profile onto the device.
</li></ul>
Some MDM products include a server component that provides a web-based service for users to initiate this process, while others initiate the process by requiring users to download a particular MDM client app from the App Store which can facilitate the process.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
Transmission and data formats used by the MDM protocol are thoroughly standards-based. Detailed, authoritative description of the transactions between the device and the enterprise are available to Apple-registered developers at <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">https://developer.apple.com</b>.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
Additional description and security analysis is available in <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">https://github.com/intrepidusgroup/imdmtools/blob/master/Presentations/InsideAppleMDM_ShmooCon_2012.pdf</b>, linked from <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">intrepidusgroup.com/insight/2012/01/changes-to-apple-mdm-for-ios-5-x/</b>.
</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="manual_deployment_with_iphone_configuration_utility"><title>Manual Deployment with iPhone Configuration Utility</title><description> Manually using the iPhone Configuration Utility (iPCU) is the
safest means of deploying configuration profiles to devices, but does not scale
well as it depends on administrators’ manual intervention. It also implies that
an MDM server will not be used to remotely monitor device status. Nevertheless,
transferring the profile to a device which is directly connected via USB cable
avoids threats to confidentiality and integrity inherent in network transfers.
</description><rationale> iPCU is available at <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://www.apple.com/support/iphone/enterprise/</b> (cryptographic checksum unavailable). Documentation is available at <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://help.apple.com/iosdeployment-ipcu/</b>.
</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="avoid_unauthenticated_unencrypted_deployment_methods"><title>Avoid Unauthenticated, Unencrypted Deployment Methods</title><description> Avoid deployment of configuration profiles through methods that
do not provide encryption and authentication. Email is especially discouraged.
</description><rationale> It is possible to distribute configuration profiles to individual
devices by emailing the profile to the user of the device or providing a link
via SMS. Once the profile is accepted by the end user, the iOS device
facilitates its installation. These methods are not recommended because they do
not generally provide authentication of the sender of the configuration
profile, or encryption of the profile itself during transmission. Users should
generally be taught not to have confidence about the origin of email
attachments or SMS messages.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
Emailing configuration profiles also presupposes that the user has configured an email account on the iPhone.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
Furthermore, once the configuration profile is in the receiver’s mailbox, it will remain there until it is manually deleted. If the mobile profile contains sensitive information, its prolonged existence in an unmanaged mailbox poses additional risk.</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
    </Group>
  </Group>
  <Group id="settings"><title>System Settings</title>
    
    <Group id="passcode"><title>Passcode</title><description> The remarkable attention paid to passcode quality requirements
represents misplaced priorities in the current network environment, as
passcodes do not protect against many contemporary threats. However, setting a
passcode enables cryptographic features that can protect data on the device if
it is lost, stolen or temporarily out of possession. Hardware and software
cryptographic features of iOS devices – not present on typical desktop or
server systems – provide significant protections against the password-guessing
threat when the passcode feature is enabled. Furthermore, iOS devices are
likely to store only a single user’s credentials, while complex passcode
policies are designed to protect against the compromise of large numbers of
credentials when they are stored on a single system that becomes compromised
(such as a directory server). Onerous passcode policies may also drive users to
attempt to subvert the settings. For these reasons, IT decision makers should
understand that onerous passcode policies on iOS devices provide little value
(in the best case), and may end up being counterproductive.

The following publicly-available research provides rationale for these recommendations:
<ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li><i>Apple iOS 4 Security Evaluation</i> by Dino Dai Zovi at: 
<b>http://www.trailofbits.com/resources/ios4_security_evaluation_slides.pdf</b>. The slides’ section “Attacking Passcode” provides highly relevant platform-specific discussion for iOS devices.
</li><li>NIST Special Publication 800-118 <i>DRAFT Guide to Enterprise Password
Management</i> at
<b>http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/PubsDrafts.html#SP-800-118</b> provides
discussion about factors that should be considered in order to create effective
password strength recommendations.
</li></ul>
</description>
      
      
      <Group id="enable_passcode"><title>Enable Passcode</title><description> The following passcode settings are recommended, and can be
deployed via a configuration profile. </description>
        
        
        <Rule id="disable_simple_value_for_passcode" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Simple Value for Passcode</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow simple value</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Unchecked</b>. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">IA-5(1)</reference><rationale>Disabling the use of simple values for a passcode enables display
of the entire keyboard for passcode entry, instead of only a numeric keypad.
</rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="require_alphanumeric_value_for_passcode" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Require Alphanumeric Value for Passcode</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Require alphanumeric value</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Checked</b>. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">IA-5(1)</reference><rationale> Requiring alphanumeric values should increase the search space in a
password-guessing attack. </rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="set_minimum_passcode_length" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Set Minimum Passcode Length</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Minimum passcode length</b> to a value. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">IA-5(1)</reference><rationale> Setting a minimum length should increase the search space in a
password-guessing attack. A passcode length between 4 and 6 may be a reasonable balance
between user experience and security for many deployment scenarios.
</rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="set_minimum_number_of_complex_characters" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Set Minimum Number of Complex Characters</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Minimum number of complex characters</b> to a value.
</description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">IA-5(1)</reference><rationale> Requiring complex characters should increase the search space in a
password-guessing attack. </rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="set_maximum_passcode_age" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Set Maximum Passcode Age</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Maximum passcode age</b> to a number of a days, if there is a need
for such rotation. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">IA-5(1)</reference><rationale> Changing passcodes prevents an attacker who has
compromised the password from re-using it to regain access. This is an unlikely
scenario, but is addressed by setting a password expiration. A value of 120 days is
likely to be adequate for many deployment scenarios.</rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="set_auto_lock_time" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Set Auto-Lock Time</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Auto-Lock (in minutes)</b> to a number of minutes.
A value of 5 minutes may be a reasonable balance
between user experience and security for many deployment scenarios.
</description><rationale>Automatically locking the device after a period of inactivity
ensures that the device will require passcode entry if lost or left unattended. 
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="set_passcode_history" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Set Passcode History</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Passcode History</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">3</b>. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">IA-5(1)</reference><rationale>Setting a passcode history ensures that users cannot trivially
alternate between passcodes.</rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="set_grace_period_for_device_lock" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Set Grace Period for Device Lock</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Grace period for device lock</b> to 5 minutes, or less.
</description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">IA-11</reference><rationale> This permits unlock of the device after a certain period of time
has passed since the last device lock. Allowing a Grace Period enhances
usability and makes users more likely to tolerate passcode requirements.
</rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="set_maximum_number_of_failed_attempts" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Set Maximum Number of Failed Attempts</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Maximum number of failed attempts</b> to 10 attempts, or
fewer. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">IA-5(1)</reference><rationale> Setting the device to automatically erase after a number of failed
attempts can protect against witless password guessing attacks conducted
through the unlock screen. 
</rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
      </Group>
      <Group id="understand_which_files_are_protected_by_encryption"><title>Understand Which Files are Protected by Encryption</title><description> Enabling a passcode activates the Data Protection feature of iOS.
The Data Protection feature encrypts items with a key whose availability
depends on entry of the passcode. Currently, the following items are protected:
<ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li><b>Email messages</b> stored by the built-in Mail app </li><li><b>Inactive Apps’ Screenshots</b> displayed at app re-launch to create
impression of “instant resume” </li><li><b>Some Keychain Items</b> such as email passwords and iTunes backup password </li><li><b>Data stored by third-party apps</b> which use the Data Protection API </li></ul>
</description><rationale> In fact, the rest of the files on the device are encrypted, but
they are still available to an attacker who can get privileged code to execute
on the device. This is because the encryption key for these files is available
even without the passcode (unlike the files above).

This was possible for a time using publicly-available tools which provide the ability
to execute privileged code on any device in physical possession. Examples of
these tools include jailbreak software such as <i xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">evasi0n</i> from the evad3rs
and <i xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">redsn0w</i> from The iPhone Dev Team. These applications leverage a
collection of exploits and other jailbreak utilities including <i xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">limera1n</i>
by George Hotz (geohot).

Note also that even if privileged code can be run by an attacker on a lost or
stolen iPhone, a password-guessing attack against the protected files must be
executed on the device itself. This is because the key which encrypts the items
listed above is derived from the passcode as well as a key that is bound to the
hardware of the device (and not considered extricable from it).

The following references provide detailed explanation:
<ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li><i>iPhone data protection in depth</i> by Jean-Baptiste Bédrune and Jean Sigwald
(Sogeti ESEC) available at <b>http://esec-lab.sogeti.com/dotclear/public/publications/11-hitbamsterdam-iphonedataprotection.pdf</b> linked from <b>http://esec-lab.sogeti.com/post/iOS-5-data-protection-updates</b>.
</li><li><i>Apple iOS 4 Security Evaluation</i> by Dino Dai Zovi (Trail of Bits)
available at <b>http://trailofbits.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/apple-ios-4-security-evaluation-whitepaper.pdf</b> linked from <b>http://trailofbits.wordpress.com/2011/08/10/ios-4-security-evaluation/</b>.
</li></ul>
</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
    </Group>
    <Group id="restrictions"><title>Restrictions</title><description> Some security-relevant restrictions can be placed upon the user
of the iOS device. </description>
      
      
      <Group id="device_functionality"><title>Device Functionality</title>
        
        <Rule id="disable_installation_of_third_party_apps" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Installation of Third-Party Apps</title><description> Unless necessary, disable <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow installing apps</b>. This is
unusual for a general-purpose device. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">CM-11(2)</reference><rationale> While iOS includes features such as sandboxing that are designed to
prevent third-party apps from influencing the integrity of the operating
system, they do have the ability to access data stored on the device such as
Address Book, Location Data, or the Photo Library, and have the
ability to transmit this information. </rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="disable_camera" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Camera</title><description> Disable <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow use of camera</b>, if concerns exist about
capturing sensitive images. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">SC-42</reference>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="disable_screen_capture" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Screen Capture</title><description> Disable <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow screen capture</b>, if concerns exist about
storing screen contents in the Photo Library. </description><rationale> While unlikely, this feature could accidentally be triggered (by
simultaneously pressing the Home and Sleep buttons) and lead to storage of
sensitive information outside the intended storage area.</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
      </Group>
      <Group id="applications"><title>Applications</title>
        
        <Rule id="disable_itunes_store" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable use of iTunes Store</title><description> Deselect <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow use of iTunes Store</b>, to prevent access to media content and applications.</description><rationale>iTunes provides access to media content and applications.</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Group id="safari"><title>Safari</title><description>The Safari web browser is included with iOS, and the following
section provides discussion of security-relevant settings.
Additional information about Safari security settings on
iOS is available at <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1677</b>.
</description>
          
          
          <Rule id="disable_safari" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Safari</title><description>If Safari can be disabled, uncheck <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow use of Safari</b>.
<b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><i>This is very unusual for a general-purpose device.</i></b></description><rationale>Devices in specialized use cases may not require the use of a web
browser such as Safari.
</rationale>
            
            
            
          </Rule>
          <Rule id="disable_safari_autofill" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Safari Autofill</title><description> Deselect <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Enable autofill</b>, to prevent storage of
some potentially sensitive information by Safari. </description><rationale>Storage of autofill information permits an attacker to harvest
previously-used credentials in the event that the device becomes
compromised.
</rationale>
            
            
            
          </Rule>
          <Rule id="enable_safari_fraud_warning" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable Safari Fraud Warning</title><description> Select <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Force fraud warning</b>, to ensure users are
warned when visiting known-fraudulent web sites. </description><rationale>Fraudulent web sites may try to collect sensitive information
from users.
</rationale>
            
            
            
          </Rule>
          <Rule id="disable_javascript" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable JavaScript</title><description> Deselect <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Enable javascript</b>, to prevent JavaScript from
running in Safari. <i xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This makes the Internet virtually useless and is only
appropriate for unusual, high-security scenarios.</i>
</description><rationale>JavaScript permits client-side scripts to run within the browser.
Nearly all modern web sites use JavaScript, though its functionality
constitutes an attack surface.</rationale>
            
            
            
          </Rule>
          <Rule id="enable_safari_pop_up_blocking" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable Safari Pop-up Blocking</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Block pop-ups</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Checked</b>. </description><rationale>Blocking pop-ups prevents malicious or obnoxious web sites from
interfering with the user in an unexpected and possibly security-relevant
manner.</rationale>
            
            
            
          </Rule>
          <Rule id="accept_cookies_from_visited_sites_only" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Accept Cookies from Visited Sites Only</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Accept cookies</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">From visited sites</b>.</description><rationale>Accepting cookies from only visited sites decreases the extent
to which third-party web sites can track user activity.</rationale>
            
            
            
          </Rule>
        </Group>
      </Group>
      <Group id="icloud_configuration"><title>iCloud configuration</title><description>Policies regarding the usage of cloud-based storage services
continue to evolve, as do the assurances of safety by cloud providers. In
general, if there is a need to store potentially sensitive information on the
iOS device, then the following restrictions should be considered.</description>
        
        
        <Rule id="disable_icloud_backups" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable iCloud Backups</title><description>Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow backup</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Unchecked</b>. </description><rationale>Backing up iOS devices to iCloud may involve placing enterprise data
on systems that are not controlled by the enterprise.</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="disable_icloud_document_sync" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable iCloud Document Sync</title><description>Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow document sync</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Unchecked</b>.</description><rationale>Synchronizing documents to iCloud involves placing data on systems
that are not controlled by the enterprise.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="disable_icloud_photo_stream" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable iCloud Photo Stream</title><description>Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow Photo Stream</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Unchecked</b>.</description><rationale>If photographs may constitute sensitive enterprise data, then
transferring photos to iCloud could involve placing such data on systems that
are not controlled by the enterprise.</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
      </Group>
      <Group id="security_and_privacy"><title>Security and Privacy</title>
        
        <Rule id="disable_sending_diagnostic_data_to_apple" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Sending Diagnostic Data to Apple</title><description> Disable <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow diagnositic data to be sent to Apple</b> to
Unchecked, if this presents concerns about inadvertent transmission of
sensitive data.</description><rationale>Diagnostic data could be considered sensitive in some environments
and not transmitted outside enterprise control.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="disable_user_acceptance_of_untrusted_tls_certificates" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable User Acceptance of Untrusted TLS Certificates</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow user to accept untrusted TLS certificates</b> to
Unchecked.  Root CAs trusted by iOS are available at
<b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT5012</b>.
</description><rationale>Presentation of an untrusted TLS certificate to client software
could indicate a man-in-the-middle attack.  
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="force_encrypted_backups" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Force Encrypted Backups</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Force encrypted backups</b> to Checked, in order
to ensure that the contents of iOS devices are encrypted when backed up
onto host computers.
</description><rationale>Encrypting device backups protects hosts backups even if the host
later becomes compromised.  </rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
      </Group>
    </Group>
    <Group id="wi_fi"><title>Wi-Fi</title><description> iOS devices support 802.1X authentication for WPA2 Enterprise
networks, and this is strongly recommended. A RADIUS server is required for
802.1X authentication and typically involves the use of public key
infrastructure. User education and training is also important, since the user
has control over the device’s network settings. Section  contains information
for users. DoD Instruction 8420.01, available at <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://www.dtic.mil/whs/directives/corres/pdf/842001p.pdf</b>, provides information for DoD entities regarding the configuration and deployment of WiFi networks. </description>
      
      
      <Rule id="disable_auto_join_for_wi_fi" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Auto-Join for Wi-Fi</title><description>Ensure that <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Auto Join</b> is disabled for WiFi networks.
</description><rationale> Disabling auto join ensures that users are aware of when
connections to WiFi networks are being made. </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Rule>
      <Rule id="use_wpa__wpa2_enterprise_for_wi_fi_encryption" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Use WPA / WPA2 Enterprise for Wi-Fi Encryption</title><description> Using <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">WPA / WPA2 Enterprise</b> with <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">TLS</b> for
authentication is recommended. If TLS support is not available, <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">PEAP</b> is
the next best choice for authentication. All other authentication protocols are
not recommended. </description><rationale> Use <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">WPA / WPA2</b> if authentication support is not available.
Proxy servers can be configured with WiFi as another layer for providing
control of the connection. </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Rule>
    </Group>
    <Group id="vpn"><title>VPN</title><description> VPN connectivity obviously depends on an enterprise’s available
infrastructure, but VPNs which use IPsec are preferred. Several SSL VPNs are
also supported by iOS. Actual VPNs are preferred over SSL VPNs as they are
designed to protect systemwide network communications. Note, however, that at
this time iOS VPNs cannot be configured to route all traffic through a VPN, and
operate in split tunnel mode. This behavior occurs even if <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Send All
Traffic</b> is selected as part of any VPN’s configuration. </description>
      
      
      <Rule id="select_ipsec_cisco_or_l2tp_for_use_as_vpn" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Select IPsec (Cisco) or L2TP for Use as VPN</title><description> Select <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">IPsec (Cisco)</b> or <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">L2TP</b> (which also uses
IPsec) for use as the Connection Type if possible. Use of hardware tokens is
generally preferred over passwords for user authentication. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">AC-18(1)</reference><rationale> Apple provides documentation regarding iOS VPN capabilities in the
following documents:
<ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li><i>VPN Server Configuration for iOS Devices</i>, available at:
<b>http://help.apple.com/iosdeployment-vpn/</b></li><li><i>iOS: Supported protocols for VPN</i>, available at:
<b>http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1288</b></li></ul>
The following documents provide recommendations for configuring VPNs
in an enterprise infrastructure:
<ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li><i>Guide to IPSec VPNs</i> (NIST SP 800-77), available at: 
<b>http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-77/sp800-77.pdf</b>.
</li><li><i>Guide to SSL VPNs</i> (NIST SP 800-113), available at:
<b>http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-113/SP800-113.pdf</b>.
</li></ul>
</rationale>
        
        
        
        
      </Rule>
    </Group>
    <Group id="email"><title>Email</title><description> Permitting users to access only enterprise-supported email
accounts decreases the risk posed by email-based attacks. It ensures that
enterprise-provided countermeasures against email attacks (such as content
filters or anti-virus software) can scan email transmitted to the device.
</description>
      
      
      <Rule id="prevent_moving_messages_between_mail_accounts" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Prevent Moving Messages between Mail Accounts</title><description> Disable <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow Move</b> for all email accounts. </description><rationale>Moving mail directly between accounts could permit the movement of
enterprise information to personal email accounts.  While this is possible
simply through email forwarding, in that case the enterprise email server (when
used as the MTA) has at least the possibility of logging such transfers.
</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Rule>
      <Rule id="enable_s_mime_support_for_mail_if_needed" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable S/MIME Support for Mail if Needed</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Enable S/MIME</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Checked</b>, to provide encrypted and
authenticated email support. Ensure that transmission of
configuration profiles to devices is encrypted and authenticated if S/MIME
certificates containing private keys are embedded. The iOS device can also be
configured to use an SCEP server to retrieve S/MIME certificates for use with
Mail.</description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">SI-7(6)</reference><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">SC-8</reference><rationale>S/MIME provides the capability for users to send and receive S/MIME
email messages from wireless email devices. S/MIME and digital signatures
provide assurance the message is authentic. Without S/MIME users will not be
able to read encrypted email and will not be able to encrypt email with
sensitive information.
</rationale>
        
        
        
        
      </Rule>
      <Rule id="enable_ssl_for_mail_connections" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable SSL for Mail Connections</title><description> Ensure <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Use SSL</b> is enabled for all incoming and outgoing
email accounts.</description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">SI-7(6)</reference><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">SC-8</reference><rationale>SSL provides authentication of the mail server to
which the mail client connects, and also encrypts traffic between the mail
server and the email client.
</rationale>
        
        
        
        
      </Rule>
    </Group>
    <Group id="exchange_activesync"><title>Exchange ActiveSync</title><description> If your organization employs Microsoft Exchange to manage user
accounts and maintain device policies, configuring Exchange ActiveSync will
bind the device to the user’s Microsoft Exchange account, syncing email,
calendars and contacts with the device. </description>
      
      
      <Rule id="prevent_moving_messages_between_activesync_accounts" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Prevent moving messages between ActiveSync accounts</title><description> Disable <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Allow Move</b> for all Exchange ActiveSync accounts.
</description>
        
        
      </Rule>
      <Rule id="allow_mail_from_this_account_only_from_the_mail_app" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Mail from this Account Only from the Mail App</title><description> Enable <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Use Only in Mail</b> for all Exchange ActiveSync
accounts. </description>
        
        
      </Rule>
      <Rule id="enable_ssl_for_activesync_communications" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable SSL for ActiveSync Communications</title><description> Ensure <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Use SSL</b> is <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Checked</b> for all Exchange ActiveSync
accounts. </description>
        
        
      </Rule>
      <Rule id="enable_s_mime_support_for_activesync_if_needed" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable S/MIME Support for ActiveSync if Needed</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Enable S/MIME</b> to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Checked</b>, if encrypted and
authenticated email support is needed. Ensure that transmission of
configuration profiles to devices is encrypted and authenticated if S/MIME
certificates containing private keys are embedded. The iOS device can also be
configured to use an SCEP server to retrieve S/MIME certificates for use with
Mail. </description>
        
        
      </Rule>
    </Group>
    <Group id="ldap"><title>LDAP</title>
      
      <Rule id="enable_ssl_for_ldap_connections" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable SSL for LDAP Connections</title><description> Ensure <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Use SSL</b> is enabled if using an LDAP service.
</description><rationale>SSL provides authentication of the LDAP server to
which the system connects, and also encrypts traffic between the iOS device
and the LDAP server.
</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Rule>
    </Group>
    <Group id="webdav"><title>Calendars and Address Books</title>
      
      <Group id="caldav"><title>CalDav</title>
        
        <Rule id="enable_ssl_for_caldav_connections" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable SSL for CalDav Connections</title><description> Ensure <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Use SSL</b> is enabled if using a CalDav service.
</description><rationale>SSL provides authentication of the CalDav server to
which the iOS device connects, and also encrypts traffic between the CalDav
server and the iOS device.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
      </Group>
      <Group id="subscribed_calendars"><title>Subscribed Calendars</title>
        
        <Rule id="enable_ssl_for_subscribed_calendar_connections" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable SSL for Subscribed Calendar Connections</title><description> Ensure <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Use SSL</b> is enabled if connecting to calendar
subscriptions.</description><rationale>SSL provides authentication of servers that provide calender
subscriptions, and also encrypts traffic between the calendar subscription
server and the iOS device.</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
      </Group>
      <Group id="carddav"><title>CardDav</title>
        
        <Rule id="enable_ssl_for_carddav_connections" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Enable SSL for CardDav Connections</title><description> Enable <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Use SSL</b> if using a CardDav service. </description><rationale>SSL provides authentication of the CardDav server to
which the iOS device connects, and also encrypts traffic between the CardDav
server and the email client.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
      </Group>
    </Group>
    <Group id="certs"><title>Certificates</title>
      
      <Group id="credentials"><title>Credentials</title><description> If your organization employs any self-signed certificates, embed
them in the configuration profile or use SCEP to distribute.
Note that embeddeding any credentials into the configuration profile introduces
the need for encryption during profile deployment.
</description>
        
        
        <Group id="scep"><title>SCEP</title><description> If your organization will use the Simple Certificate Enrollment
Protocol to distribute certificates and configuration profiles, include its
settings with the configuration profile. These settings may be handled by MDM
products in a manner that is automated, and not tied to individual users.
</description>
          
          
          <Rule id="set_a_challenge_password" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Set a Challenge Password</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Challenge</b> field, enter a strong passphrase to be
used as a pre-shared secret for automatic enrollment. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">IA-2(2)</reference>
            
            
            
          </Rule>
        </Group>
      </Group>
    </Group>
    <Group id="mobile_device_management"><title>Mobile Device Management</title><description> Some behavior of Mobile Device Management (MDM) software can be
configured inside a configuration profile. This includes how much information
an MDM server can retrieve from a device, whether an MDM server can update
profiles remotely, whether an MDM server can remotely wipe a device, and
whether an MDM server can reset a device’s password. These settings allow for
more fine-grained adjustment between enterprise control versus user control of
a device. Some MDM products may not permit administrators to disable some of
their capability for querying devices.  Information about enterprise deployment
using MDM is available from Apple at
<b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://www.apple.com/ipad/business/it-center/deployment-mdm.html</b>.
</description>
      
      
      <Group id="sign_messages"><title>Sign Messages</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Sign messages</b> to Checked. </description><rationale> This setting causes responses generated by the device (in response
to commands from the MDM server) to be signed with the device’s identity
certificate. </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="check_out_when_removed"><title>Check Out When Removed</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Check out when removed</b> to Checked. </description><rationale> This causes the device to send a message to the MDM server whenever
the configuration profile is removed. </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="access_rights_for_remote_administrators"><title>Access Rights for Remote Administrators</title><description> The following settings control what an MDM server is permitted to
query from an iOS device. For an enterprise-owned, enterprise-controlled
device, permitting the enterprise administrator to query as much information as
possible is appropriate. Some MDM products may simply include these access
rights by default and offer options to retrieve less information from the
device.  

<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
At the same time, querying all of these types of information may not be
appropriate even for some enterprise users, and for enterprises that support
BYOD scenarios. The terms of any individual organization’s “BYOD Contract” with
their users is beyond the scope of this document. </description>
        
        
        <Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_general_settings" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Query of General Settings</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Query device for</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">General
settings</b> to Checked. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">CA-9</reference><rationale>ALlowing an enterprise to be able to query general device settings
such as profile names and identifiers permits the enterprise to have insight
into the ownership of profiles installed onto the device.
</rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_security_settings" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Query of Security Settings</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Query device for</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Security
settings</b> to Checked. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">CA-9</reference><rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query security settings
permits the enterprise to have insight into the device's security posture.
</rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_network_settings" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Query of Network Settings</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Query device for</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Network
settings</b> to Checked. </description><rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query network settings
permits the enterprise to have insight into the device's network
connection capabilities.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_restrictions" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Query of Restrictions</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Query device for</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Restriction</b> to
Checked. </description><rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query restrictions
enforced on the device permits the enterprise to have insight into
whether certain device behavior is configured, such as encrypted
backups.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_configuration_profiles" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Query of Configuration Profiles</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Query device for</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Configuration
Profiles</b> to Checked. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">CA-9</reference><rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query installed configuration
profiles permits the enterprise to understand the overall composed configuration
applied to the device.
</rationale>
          
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_applications" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Query of Applications</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Query device for</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Applications</b>
to Checked. </description><rationale>Allowing an enterprise to query installed applications 
provides insight into the device's software inventory, which is valuable
in incident response.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_provisioning_profiles" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Query of Provisioning Profiles</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Query device for</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Provisioning
Profiles</b> to Checked. </description><rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query installed provisioning
profiles permits the enterprise to be aware of expiry dates
for these.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_configuration_profiles" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Addition/Removal of Configuration Profiles</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Add / Remove</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Configuration
Profiles</b> to Checked. </description><rationale> Allowing an enterprise to add or remove configuration profiles
permits an enterprise MDM server to be able to update these profiles remotely.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_provisioning_profiles" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Addition/Removal of Provisioning Profiles</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Add / Remove</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Provisioning
Profiles</b> to Checked. </description><rationale> Allowing an enterprise to add or remove provisioning profiles
permits an enterprise MDM server to be able to update these profiles remotely.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_apps" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Addition/Removal of Apps</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Add / Remove</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Apps</b>
to Checked.  This applies to managed apps, which are purchased by
the enterprise via the Volume Purchasing Program.
</description><rationale> Allowing an enterprise to add or remove managed apps provides the
enterprise with the ability to easily deploy enterprise applications to
devices. The MDM server can also specify that the data in managed apps be
removed when the MDM profile is removed, to protect enterprise data.</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_settings" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Addition/Removal of Settings</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Add / Remove</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings</b> to Checked.
</description><rationale>Allowing an enterprise to add or remove settings
provides agility with regard to individual settings management.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_or_disallow_remote_change_of_device_password" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow or Disallow Remote Change of Device Password</title><description> In the <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Security</b> section, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Change device password</b>
to Unchecked or Checked. This entails a risk decision, though Checked is likely
to be appropriate for most scenarios. </description><rationale> Most enterprises are likely well-served by permitting the MDM
administrator to remotely send a change password command, in order to allow
users with forgotten passcodes to maintain access to their devices. This would
also permit an enterprise with appropriate authority, and which needed to
overcome the Data Protection feature (such as for forensics purposes) the
ability to do so.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
At the same time, an attacker who has compromised communications between the
device and its MDM server (or the MDM server itself), could maliciously send a
password-change command to defeat the data-at-rest protection on the devices.
This would depend upon an attacker’s physical compromise of the device as well
as compromise of TLS communications (or the MDM server itself).
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
        <Rule id="allow_remote_wipe" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Allow Remote Wipe</title><description> Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Remote wipe</b> to Checked. </description><rationale>Permitting remote wipe allows the enterprise to remotely wipe an iOS
device in the event that it is lost or stolen.
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
<br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/>
Note also that a layered configuration profile approach which involves specific
configuration profiles permitting access to specific services (which can be
removed by an MDM server), effectively permits selective removal of access to
services (and their local data). This can provide a form of remote wipe that is
more appropriate with BYOD scenarios that are incompatible with IT staff wiping
entire devices.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Rule>
      </Group>
    </Group>
    <Group id="manually_configured_device_settings"><title>Manually-Configured Device Settings</title><description> The following security-relevant settings can be manually applied.
These settings depend on the user’s control of the device, and thus training
users can help them make appropriate choices. </description>
      
      
      <Rule id="disable_wi_fi_if_practical" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Wi-Fi, if Practical</title><description> If the iOS device is not to be connected to a Wi-Fi network,
disable Wi-Fi. Set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings &gt; Wi-Fi &gt; Off</b>. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">AC-18(3)</reference><rationale> Disabling <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Ask to Join Networks</b> will prevent the phone from
automatically associating with previously known (but potentially-spoofed)
access points without user interaction, and should be disabled whenever
possible. Users should be instructed to use only trusted WiFi networks.
</rationale>
        
        
        
        
      </Rule>
      <Rule id="disable_bluetooth_manually_if_practical" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Bluetooth Manually, if Practical</title><description> To disable Bluetooth, set <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings &gt; Bluetooth &gt; Off</b>, when practical. </description><reference href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-53-Rev3/sp800-53-rev3-final.pdf">AC-18(3)</reference><rationale> Leaving Bluetooth enabled can expose the presence of an iOS device,
although the device provides visual cues when it is in the Bluetooth
“discoverable” mode which allows it to pair with other devices. The Bluetooth
profiles supported by iOS are described at <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT3647</b>.
</rationale>
        
        
        
        
      </Rule>
      <Rule id="disable_location_services_if_practical" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Location Services, if Practical</title><description> If the ability of apps and web pages to determine the location of
the device poses an unacceptable risk, disable Location Services. Set
<b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings &gt; General &gt; Restrictions &gt; Privacy: Location Services &gt; Off</b>. Note also that
usage of Location Service can be controlled on a per-app basis, at the user’s
discretion. Given the utility of location information for some apps (such as
Maps), user-determined settings may be most practical. </description><rationale> If an application (such as Maps) wishes to use Location Services
while being disabled, the user will be prompted to return to <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings</b> to
enable it. </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Rule>
      <Rule id="disable_loading_of_remote_images_if_practical" severity="low" selected="false"><title>Disable Loading of Remote Images, if Practical</title><description> To disable the automatic loading of images in e-mail, set
<b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings &gt; Mail, Contacts, Calendars&gt; Mail: Load Remote Images &gt; Off </b>
, if this is practical. </description><rationale> Automatically loading images in e-mail messages can leak usage
information to authors of fraudulent e-mail. It can also provide an opportunity
for malicious images to exploit any implementation flaws in complex graphics
libraries. At the same time, this may also inhibit viewing of images that are
useful. </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Rule>
    </Group>
  </Group>
  <Group id="device_usage_and_handling"><title>Device Usage and Handling</title><description> This chapter provides recommendations on device usage and
handling, for both administrators and users. Section  provides handling and
usage guidance for administrators. These topics include issuing devices,
managing and accounting for devices once in users’ hands, and effectively
educating users on secure device usage.  Further, there are important
recommendations such as maintaining physical control of the device, not
jailbreaking the device, and preventing connections to untrusted networks. This
section closes with suggested usage statements that could be provided to users.
</description>
    
    
    <Group id="handling_guidance_for_administrators"><title>Handling Guidance for Administrators</title><description> If the enterprise is planning to procure and distribute devices
to users, administrators should establish procedures for this activity. Some
items from this section may not apply to BYOD scenarios, however, such as
inventory management and prompt retirement of unsupported devices.
</description>
      
      
      <Group id="establish_a_user_training_program"><title>Establish a User Training Program</title><description> Create or make available training resources to educate users
about device security issues and organization policies. Ensure that all device
users are aware of risks and properly trained to mitigate them. </description><rationale> Security and policy awareness training reduces the risk of
user-originated security compromise. This relates closely to any agreements
between the user and enterprise regarding device handling, which should be
verified for each user prior to their being issued a device, as described in
Section . </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="issuing_devices"><title>Issuing Devices</title><description> This section provides recommendations for enterprises issuing iOS
devices. </description>
        
        
        <Group id="issue_only_supported_devices"><title>Issue Only Supported Devices</title><description> Ensure that only supported hardware versions are issued.
Supported hardware versions are defined as those that can run the latest
version of iOS and receive all updates. To determine this, administrators will
need to manually note which systems can be updated whenever security updates
are provided. </description><rationale> Sometimes only the current version and the previous version of the
iPhone or iPad hardware can run all updates. This suggests that IT planners
should anticipate a 2 year (or 3 year, at most) refresh cycle for
enterprise-purchased devices. </rationale>
          
          
          
        </Group>
        <Group id="erase_and_reset_devices_if_re_issuing"><title>Erase and Reset Devices, if Re-issuing</title><description> If re-issuing devices, erase them before distributing them to
users. </description><rationale> Use the command <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings &gt; General &gt; Reset &gt; Erase All
Content and Settings</b> to erase a device. Clearing content and settings
returns the device to a stable state and prevents accidental exposure of the
prior user’s data. </rationale>
          
          
          
        </Group>
        <Group id="update_device_to_user_registration"><title>Update Device-to-User Registration</title><description> Establish a system for attributing individual devices to users
prior to issuance. This information must be updated every time a device is
issued or transferred. Existing inventory tracking systems or MDM software can
enable automation of this process. The following pieces of information from
each device can be useful: <ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li>UDID (Unique Device Identifier) </li><li>Serial Number </li><li>IMEI (if equipped with a cellular connectivity)
</li><li>Model Number </li><li>Wi-Fi MAC Address </li><li>Bluetooth MAC
Address </li></ul>MDM products may also report this information. This
information should be protected accordingly. </description>
          
          
        </Group>
        <Group id="verify_user_training_history"><title>Verify User Training History</title><description> Ensure that users are familiar with the training before receiving
a new device, and at regular intervals afterward. </description>
          
          
        </Group>
        <Group id="provide_recharging_hardware_with_device"><title>Provide Recharging Hardware with Device</title><description> Distribute AC power adapters to users when issuing devices and
warn users not to connect their devices to unauthorized systems. It may be
prudent to distribute additional AC power adapters to remove the temptation to
connect the devices to unknown PCs. </description><rationale> Connecting iOS devices to unauthorized systems, even if only
intending to recharge the device, presents a security risk. Providing a power
adapter, and easy access to replacements and additional adapters, will help
combat temptation to connect to other systems. Users should never be left with
connecting to a computer as their only option to recharge their device.
</rationale>
          
          
          
        </Group>
      </Group>
      <Group id="dealing_with_a_lost_or_stolen_ios_device"><title>Dealing with a Lost or Stolen iOS Device</title><description> If an iOS device is reported as lost or stolen, the device should
be immediately disabled to prevent unauthorized use or access. The system
administrator can issue a remote “Wipe” command to erase all media, data and
settings from the device, restoring it to factory settings. Be aware of the
circumstances under which issuing a wipe may not be possible, such as keeping a
device in Airplane Mode or simply lacking network connectivity. </description>
        
        
        <Group id="establish_procedure_for_lost_or_stolen_ios_devices"><title>Establish Procedure for Lost or Stolen iOS devices</title><description> Establish and test a procedure to issue a wipe command to erase
data from a lost or stolen iOS device. Ensure that users are also aware of
their responsibilities to report lost or stolen devices. Wipe commands can 
be issued by an MDM server or by Exchange ActiveSync. Users can also initiate 
remote wipe using iCloud, if the device is enrolled. </description>
          
          
        </Group>
      </Group>
      <Group id="retire_devices_which_cannot_run_latest_os_version"><title>Retire Devices Which Cannot Run Latest OS Version</title><description> Immediately retire any devices which cannot run the latest iOS
version. This requires vigilance on the part of administrators, to monitor when
an update is issued but is not supported on older devices. </description><rationale> iOS updates include both security patches as well as new
functionality. Ensure that all iOS device hardware provided and managed by the
enterprise can always run the latest iOS. For example, all iPhone 3G devices
should be immediately retired, because they cannot run iOS 6. </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="monitor_devices_using_mdm_especially_for_updates"><title>Monitor Devices Using MDM, Especially for Updates</title><description> MDM products enable enterprise integration and reporting for 
iOS devices. Regularly monitor the status of devices using MDM software and 
respond accordingly. Particularly important is
ensuring that the version of iOS is kept up to date, which implies that all
available security updates are installed. Some MDM products include the ability
to disable access to enterprise resources if devices are not kept up to date or
are otherwise not compliant. </description>
        
        
      </Group>
    </Group>
    <Group id="handling_guidance_for_users"><title>Handling Guidance for Users</title><description> User education is one of the strongest tools an organization can
use to minimize the risk of security issues. Educating users helps raise
awareness of their actions and helps them understand the reasoning behind
policy decisions. This section details physical handling guidance and security
policy topics to be reinforced to users through an organization-developed user
education program. </description>
      
      
      <Group id="physical_control"><title>Physical Control</title><description> Maintain physical control of your iOS device at all times.
</description><rationale> All guidance contained in this document depends upon uninterrupted
physical control of your iOS device. It is your responsibility to maintain
possession of the device. Never leave your iOS device unattended in an insecure
location. An unattended device is at high risk for loss, theft, and other forms
of compromise that could violate the confidentiality, integrity, or
availability of the device and the information contained therein. </rationale>
        
        
        
        <Group id="surrendering_physical_control"><title>Surrendering Physical Control</title><description> Learn the proper procedure for relinquishing control of the iOS
device to another entity. </description><rationale> There are times when physical control of the iOS device must be
surrendered, such as when passing through security or customs inspections. The
following are possible methods of mitigating potential loss of personal,
financial or company information. <ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li>Before entering security or customs
checkpoints, power down the iOS device, remove its SIM card using the SIM eject
tool or an unwound paper clip, and place the SIM card in a physically separate
location such as a bag or your coat pocket. </li><li>Place the device in a
clear, tamper evident bag. </li><li>Ensure passcode is enabled.
</li></ul>Organizations may elect to require all of these steps based on their
security policy. </rationale>
          
          
          
        </Group>
        <Group id="notify_security_or_administrative_personnel_upon_loss_of_physical_control"><title>Notify Security or Administrative Personnel Upon Loss of Physical
Control</title><description> Obtain the contact information of your System Security Officer
(SSO) for use in reporting the loss of physical control of your iOS device and
learn which scenarios require SSO notification. If there is any suspicion that
a device has been accessed by an unauthorized user, report the incident
immediately to the appropriate SSO or administrative personnel. </description><rationale> If a device is lost or stolen, the administrator or SSO should be
contacted immediately in order to execute the remote wipe procedure through
Microsoft Exchange, and to create a detailed incident
report describing the event. Even if you lose control of your iOS device for a
period of time but regain it later, it should be inspected for signs of
physical compromise by system administration or security personnel. If a
compromise is suspected, actions should be taken to sanitize or destroy the
device, depending on the sensitivity of the data and severity of the situation
in which it was compromised. </rationale>
          
          
          
        </Group>
        <Group id="be_aware_of_your_surroundings"><title>Be Aware of Your Surroundings</title><description> Be aware of the danger of “shoulder surfing,” which refers to the
ability of others to see your entry or viewing of sensitive information on the
phone. </description><rationale> Because anyone nearby can potentially view any information
displayed on the device, be wary of your environment when viewing any sensitive
information, and particularly wary when entering passwords. Due to obvious
physical and user interface constraints, password entry is susceptible to
shoulder surfing, whether by observation of finger position or brief display of
each character on-screen. Some third-party products may be available to
mitigate this risk. </rationale>
          
          
          
        </Group>
        <Group id="follow_procedures_for_secure_areas"><title>Follow Procedures for Secure Areas</title><description> Learn the proper procedure for handling your iOS device in a
secure area. </description><rationale> If your organization has a secure area for talking about
confidential information, you should be educated about the risks of bringing
your iOS device into those areas. The following policies may be implemented for
device security in secure areas: <ul xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><li>Leave iOS devices outside conference
rooms. </li><li>Applications that record audio or video must be removed or
their use restricted. </li><li>Ensure the camera on the back of the iOS device
is blocked (e.g. opaque tape) to prevent photo or video recording. </li><li>Ensure that all iOS devices, if present, are in airplane mode with Wi-Fi
turned off. </li></ul> </rationale>
          
          
          
        </Group>
      </Group>
      <Group id="do_not_jailbreak_or_unlock_your_ios_device"><title>Do Not Jailbreak or Unlock Your iOS Device</title><description> Jailbreaking is a term that describes the process of modifying
the iOS device’s operating system, often with the goal of running unsigned code
or performing unsupported customizations to the operating system. Unlocking
allows users to operate an iOS device on a cellular network it is not
authorized to connect to. Unlocking an iOS device requires a jailbroken iOS
device first. </description><warning><b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Do not jailbreak or unlock your iOS device.</b> Doing so makes it
much easier for attackers to introduce malicious code onto the device.
</warning><rationale>Jailbreaking significantly increases the iOS device’s
susceptibility to compromise. It disables the enforcement of code signatures, a
critical security feature. This enables access to a wide range of software with
little accountability and minimal vetting. Jailbreaking tools also typically
install and activates services that make the device easier to remotely access,
such as SSH. </rationale>
        
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="install_software_updates_when_available"><title>Install Software Updates When Available</title><description> Install software updates as quickly as possible. Updates can be
applied over-the-air, and are indicated by a red circle on the "Settings" app.
Apply by following <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Settings &gt; General &gt; Software Update</b>.
</description><rationale> Software updates for iOS devices can contain fixes for security
vulnerabilities. As these vulnerabilities often become public knowledge when
the updates are released, installing updates as soon as they are available is
strongly recommended. Supported 3rd party software should not be broken by
updates. Prior to iOS 5, applying iOS updates always required the use of
iTunes. Migrating from iOS 5 to iOS 6 also requires the use of iTunes.
</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="connect_only_to_trusted_networks"><title>Connect Only to Trusted Networks</title><description> Do not connect your iOS device to untrusted wireless networks.
</description><rationale> Connections to untrusted WiFi networks introduce some risks.
Attacks on the iOS device, or eavesdropping on the data it transmits, can occur
due to use of such networks. Because the user controls the WiFi settings, he or
she must understand the risks associated with untrusted wireless networks and
behave responsibly. Some organizations have policies that forbid connection to
non-enterprise controlled networks. Other organizations forbid or prevent the
use of personal devices on enterprise networks. </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="email_accounts"><title>Email Accounts</title>
        
        <Group id="consider_risks_of_using_personal_email_accounts"><title>Consider Risks of Using Personal Email Accounts</title><description> Do not add personal email accounts to your iOS device, unless you
are comfortable with (or approved for) the additional risk. </description><rationale> Adding personal email accounts implies that personal, non-company
data will be transferred to and stored on the device. This likely violates
organizational policy with regard to use of company resources for personal use,
but it also increases risk. It increases the risk of your personal information
being compromised as a result of an attack against the device, and also
increases the risks of company information being compromised as a result of an
attack carried out against your personal email account. See the next section
for more information about phishing attacks and the motivation for segregating
email accounts between different systems. </rationale>
          
          
          
        </Group>
        <Group id="be_aware_of_phishing"><title>Be Aware of Phishing</title><description> Be aware of phishing attempts, including receiving mobile
profiles from attackers. </description><rationale> Phishing is a term referring to a fraudulent communication (usually
email) pretending to be from a reputable source asking for personal, financial
or company information. Adding personal email accounts to your iOS device
greatly increases your availability to receive phishing emails, which may
accidentally release important information about yourself or your organization.
By removing personal email accounts from the device, you are protecting your
organization from divulging information through your device to these malicious
actors. </rationale>
          
          
          
        </Group>
      </Group>
      <Group id="disable_bluetooth_if_practical"><title>Disable Bluetooth if Practical</title><description> Disable Bluetooth communication if not necessary. </description><rationale> Disabling Bluetooth reduces the possible attack surface for
exploitation, although such vulnerabilities are rare and the iOS over-the-air
update process enables rapid patching upon any public disclosure. Bluetooth
also permits wireless device discovery and can be used to reveal a limited
amount of information from the device. If practical, it is safest to keep
Bluetooth disabled. The Bluetooth profiles available on iOS devices are
documented at <b xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT3647</b>.
</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="recharge_device_only_through_approved_methods"><title>Recharge Device Only Through Approved Methods</title><description> Recharge your device by either connecting to an
organization-approved system or by using the AC power adapter you received when
you were issued your device. </description><rationale> Connecting your iOS device to unknown systems exposes the device to
unnecessary risks, including the loss of personal or company information.
Syncing only with trusted systems also helps maintain the integrity of your iOS
device. </rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
      <Group id="do_not_use_unapproved_peripherals_on_your_ios_device"><title>Do Not Use Unapproved Peripherals on Your iOS Device</title><description> Many different types of iOS device accessories are available for
use by consumers. Some of these devices allow access to a keyboard, magnetic
card reader, or USB flash drive reader.
Users should only use accessories approved for use by the enterprise.
</description><rationale> Due to the physical access nature of these accessories, security
risks may be present when attached to an iOS device. 
</rationale>
        
        
        
      </Group>
    </Group>
  </Group>
</Benchmark>
